我们现在可以通过内容提供者
While it's great that we can query our database
查询数据库了,如果我们还可以
through the content provider, it would be nice if
使用内容提供者插入数据就好了
we could also use the content provider to put
我们将从Insert函数开始
data in. We'll begin with the insert function. Let's fill
让我们用已经在其它的内容提供者函数里写过的
the insert function with the same URI matcher code
URImatcher来写insert函数
we had in the other content provider functions but with
但是这里有一点不同。我们只去匹配基本URI
one change. We're only going to match the base
对此，这里有一个很棒的理由：
URIs. There's a good reason for this. When we insert
一旦我们在数据库中插入数据，我们希望它可以
into our database, we want it to notify every
提醒所有的内容观察者数据可能被我们的插入操作改变了。
content observer that might have data modified by our
这将导致游标注册者自身通知其派生物
insert. It turns out that cursors register themselves as
这意味着根URI被通知了
notify for descendents which means that notifying the root
我们也通知了所有根URI的派生物
URI. We'll also notify all descendents of that URI.
如果我们通知是基于非根URI的
If we were to notify based on anything else
这个根URI的游标监听者
other than the root URI. Then a cursor listening
不会被通知到
on the root URI will not get notified of a
这一定会影响到它
change that would certainly impact it. So we have to
所以这样做时一定要非常谨慎
be very careful when doing that. For this reason it makes
基于这个原因，只允许插入根URI到数据库
a lot of sense to only allow insertions at our
是非常有意义的。这样一来，会非常非常容易
root URI into our database. That way, it's very, very easy
处理通知。这意味着我们不需要
to handle notifications. It means that we also don't have
为我们的插入建立一个包含了来自这个URI的参数和
to build a combination query for our insert. Containing a parameter
来自函数的其它参数的复合查询
coming from the URI. With the rest of the parameters
所以对于天气数据来说，我们只需要把
coming from a function. So for weather we just pass the
这个参数传入到insert函数中就可以了
parameters into a database insert call. We should
插入失败的话，应该抛出一个异常
throw an exception if the insert fails. The
唯一的技巧就是保证
only trick here is to make sure we
返回正确的值，这里是一个URI类型
return the correct value, which is a URI. Fortunately
幸运的是，我们已经做了一个建立URI的函数
we made a function to build these URIs
它通过ID来获取天气的路径
which contain the weather path followed by an
让我们完成它吧。
ID. Let's go task this. Once again, we
再次回到test Provider，改变我们的测试
go to test provider and we modify our test.
它是testInsertReadProvider方法
Because after all it's supposed to be test insert
这里是我们的插入语句，显然它仍然在和数据库打交道
read provider. Here's our insert statement. Obviously it's still talking
我们将让他和内容提供者去对话
to the database. We're going to want to make it
通常这是相当直接的
talk to the provider. As always, that's pretty straight forward.
我们总是使用内容解析器获取我们的provider
We always get our provider by using our content
所以我们可以用内容解析器的db来替换
resolver so we can replace this insert statement with the
这个插入语句，当然
db with a content resolver instead. And of course
我们不用内容解析器的表名
we don't use a content resolver against a table name.
我们用WeatherEntry.CONTENT_URI来代替它
Instead we do it against the WeatherEntry.content_URI.
但是仍然有一个错误。当然
But there's still something wrong. Of course, we
我们不能返回weather row ID
don't actually return the weather row ID, we
要返回URI。但是我们依然可以得到
return the URI. But we can still get a
weather row ID，怎么做呢？
weather row ID. How do we do that?
相当简单！在ContentUris里使用一个帮助类
Quite simply. Using a helper function in content
并且不需要插入
URI's, and we don't really need that insert.
毕竟我们知道，除非值是true,否则内容解析器函数
After all, we know that this content resolver function
不会返回值
isn't actually going to return unless the value is true. Now that we
现在我们就完成了。执行测试，来确保我们真的使用内容提供者
finished that, let's run the test. And make sure that we can actually
插入了数据，测试通过了
insert using our content provider. And our test passed. Well, you know what
好了，现在该轮到你来写了
time it is. Time for you to write some of this as well.